Guide to the Archives Organization File (AOF) Part 2
Archives Organization File (AOF) Part 2
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives, Cornell University Library
Archives Organization File (AOF) Part 2
5583/2
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives
74 linear ft.
Records (documents), publications (documents).
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives, Cornell University Library
Publications, manuals, policies, and plans issued by a large sample of Fortune 500 corporations and by a variety of organizations, such as professional and trade associations, government agencies, and educational and cultural organizations.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Publications, manuals, policies, and plans issued by a large sample of Fortune 500 corporations and by a variety of organizations, such as professional and trade associations, government agencies, and educational and cultural organizations. The materials issued by corporations include company histories, employee newsletters, employee benefit plans, personnel practice manuals, performance appraisal forms, affirmative action policies, training brochures, job descriptions, and career development programs as well as national trade association documents and recruitment material.
Several economic activities(sectors) are represented in the collection, such as manufacturing, transportation, mining, banking, insurance, utilities, trade, and services. Corporations whose pamphlets are held in the collection include AT&T, Bethlehem Steel, Bell Telephone System, Firestone Tire & Rubber, Ford Motor Co., General Electric, General Foods, General Mills, General Motors, Goodyear Tire & Rubber, Heinz, International Harvester, Johnson & Johnson, Lockheed Aircraft Co., Maytag Co., Metropolitan Life Insurance Co., National Association of Manufacturers, Pennsylvania Railroad Co., Radio Corporation of America (RCA), Standard Oil, Tennessee Valley Authority, Union Carbide, and Westinghouse Electric among numerous other corporations.
SUBJECTS
Names:
A. Kimball Company.; B.F. Goodrich Company.; Civil Service Commission of the City of New York.; Council of Retail Merchants (Ohio); Eli Lilly and Company.; General Electric Company. Erie Works (Erie, PA).; General Electric Company. River Works (Lynn, Mass.); General Electric Company. Pittsfield Works (Pittsfield, Mass.); General Foods Corporation.; General Mills, inc.; General Motors Corporation.; General Motors Corporation. Delco Products Division.; General Petroleum Corporation.; General Shoe Corporation.; General Telephone & Electronics Corporation.; General Telephone Company of California.; General Telephone Company of Indiana.; General Telephone Company of Michigan.; General Telephone Corporation.; Geneva Steel (Firm); Gerber Products Company.; Glass Container Manufacturers Institute.; Glenshaw Glass Company.; Globe Ticket Company.; B.F. Goodrich Company.; Goodyear Atomic Corporation.; Goodyear Tire and Rubber Company.; Grand Union Company.; Graphic Arts Employers of America.; Grumman Aircraft Engineering Corporation.; Guaranty Trust Company of New York.; H.J. Heinz Company.; Hallmark Cards, Inc.; Haloid Company.; Haloid Xerox, Inc.; Harris Trust and Savings Bank.; Harris-Intertype Corp.; Harris-Seybold Company.; Harvard University.; Hawaii Employers Council.; Hawaiian Pineapple Co.; Hercules Incorporated.; Honeywell Inc.; Hotpoint.; University of Hawaii (Honolulu). -- Industrial Relations Center.; Illinois Bell Telephone Company.; Illinois Central Industries.; Illinois Central Railroad Company.; University of Illinois at Urbana-Champaign. -- Institute of Labor and Industrial Relations.; Imperial Chemical Industries, ltd.; Imperial Oil Limited.; Industrial Accident Prevention Associations.; Industrial Association of San Francisco.; Industrial Hygiene Council.; Industrial Hygiene Foundation of America.; Ingersoll-Rand Company.; Inland Steel Company.; Institute of Life Insurance (New York, N.Y.); Institute of Management & Labor Relations.; International Business Machines Corporation.; International Nickel Company.; International Paper Company.; John Hancock Mutual Life Insurance Company.; Johns-Manville Corporation.; Johnson & Johnson.; Johnson Wax.; Jones & Laughlin Steel Corporation.; Kaiser Steel Corporation.; Kennecott Copper Corporation.; Kimberly-Clark Corporation.; Koppers Company.; Kroger Company.; Leeds and Northrup Company.; Lever Brothers Company.; Libby, McNeill & Libby.; Libby-Owens Company.; Libby-Owens-Ford Glass Company.; Liberty Mutual Insurance Company.; Liggett & Myers Tobacco Company.; Lincoln Electric Company.; Lincoln Telephone & Telegraph Company.; Lockheed Aircraft Corporation.; Lukens Steel Company.; Lumberman's Industrial Relations Committee.; Manufacturers Hanover Trust Company.; Marathon Corporation.; Marathon Oil Company.; Marquette Cement Manufacturing Company.; Marquette University.; Marshall Field & Company.; Maytag Corporation.; McCord Corporation.; McGraw-Hill Book Company.; McGraw-Hill Companies.; McGraw-Hill Publishing Company.; McKesson and Robbins, inc.; McMurray Company.; Mead Corporation.; Mead Johnson & Company.; Merchants and Manufacturers Association.; Merck & Co.; Meredith Publishing Group.; Merrill Lynch, Pierce, Fenner & Beane.; Mesta Machine Company.; Metropolitan Life Insurance Company.; Michigan Bell Telephone Company.; Michigan Central Railroad Company.; Michigan. Civil Rights Commission.; Michigan. Civil Service Commission.; Michigan. Department of Labor.; Michigan. Department of Social Services.; Michigan. Labor Mediation Board.; Minnesota Mining and Manufacturing Company.; Mobil Chemical Company.; Mobil Oil Corporation.; Mobil Overseas Oil Company.; Mobil Research and Development Corporation.; Mohawk Airlines.; Monroe Calculation Machine Company.; Monsanto Chemical Company.; Montgomery Ward.; Motorola, inc.; Mutual Life Insurance Company of New York.; Nash-Kelvinator Corporation.; National Academy of Arbitrators.; National Association of Broadcasters.; National Association of Foremen.; National Association of Furniture Manufacturers.; National Association of Manufacturers (U.S.); National Biscuit Company.; National Broadcasting Company.; National Cash Register Company.; National Coal Association.; National Committee for Full Employment (U.S.); National Consumers' League.; National Council on the Aging.; National Education Association of the United States; National Electrical Manufacturers Association.; National Farmers' Union (U.S.); National Foremen's Institute.; National Industrial Council (U.S.); National Management Association (U.S.); National Metal Trades Association (U.S.); National Restaurant Association (U.S.); National Restaurant Managers Association (U.S.); National Safety Council; National Society of Professional Engineers.; National Steel Corporation.; National Urban League.; New England Electric System.; New England Powers Association.; New England Telephone and Telegraph Company.; New Jersey Bell Telephone Company.; New Jersey Manufacturers Association.; New Jersey. Department of Civil Service.; New York (N.Y.). Department of Personnel.; New York (State). Temporary Commission Against Discrimination.; New York (State). Department of Civil Service.; New York (State). Department of Labor.; New York (State). Public Employment Relations Board.; New York (State). Workmen's Compensation Board.; New York Central Railroad Company.; New York Shipping Association.; New York State Electric and Gas Corporation.; New York Stock Exchange.; New York Telephone Company.; New York Times Company.; North American Aviation, inc.; Northeastern University (Boston, Mass.); Northwest Packers and Growers, inc.; Northwestern Bell Telephone Company.; Nunn-Bush Shoe Company.; Ohio Oil Company.; Ontario Hydro.; Organization Resources Counselors, Inc.; Owens-Corning Fiberglas Corporation.; Owens-Illinois Glass Company.; P.H. Hanes, Knitting Company.; Pacific Gas and Electric Company.; Pacific Power and Light Company.; Penn Central Merger Information Committee.; Penn Central Transportation Company.; Pennsylvania Railroad.; Peoples Gas Light and Coke Company.; Personnel Management Association of New York.; Personnel Management Association of the Northeast.; Personnel Management Association, inc.; Pfizer Inc.; Philadelphia Gas Works.; Philadelphia Rapid Transit Company.; Philadelphia Transportation Company.; Philip Morris and Company.; Phillips Petroleum Company.; Pillsbury Mills, Inc.; Pitney-Bowes, inc.; Pittsburgh Plate Glass Company.; Port of New York Authority.; Potomac Electric Power Company.; Potomac Sand & Gravel.; Procter & Gamble Company.; Prudential Insurance Company of America.; Public Personnel Association.; Public Service Corporation of New Jersey.; Public Service Electric and Gas Company.; State University of New York.; Theo. Hamm Brewing Company.; Thomas Macy & Co.; University of Michigan.; University of Minnesota.; University of Minnesota. Industrial Relations Center.; University of Mississippi.
Subjects:
Adult education; Aeronautics; Agricultural industries; Aluminum industry and trade; Airlines; Aircraft industry; Agricultural machinery; Architectural metal-work; Automobile industry and trade; Arbitration, Industrial; Agricultural chemicals industry; Audio equipment industry; Bituminous materials industry; Building trades; Buildings--Environmental engineering; Banks and banking; Breweries; Baked products industry; Business consultants; Clothing trade; Coal mines and mining; Chemical industry; Compressor industry; Clerks (Retail trade); Computer industry; Cereal products; Consumer protection; Container industry; Credit unions; Clay industries; Cement industries; Copper alloys; Dairy products industry; Detergent industry; Executives--Training of; Electric power transmission; Electronics industries; Food industry and trade; Frozen foods and industry; Footwear industry; Fruit trade; Farm produce--Marketing--Government policy; Finance, Public; Glass container industry; Glass manufacture; Gas extraction; Grain trade; Grocery trade; Gasket industry; Human capital; Hydroelectric power plants; Life insurance.; Iron industry and trade; Property insurance.; Casualty insurance.; Instructional materials industry; Health insurance.; Investment banking; Infant formula industry; Knit good industry; Labor unions; Local transit; Luggage industry; Logging; Medical supplies industry; Medicaid; Motor vehicle industry; Metal trade; Meat industry and trade; Military vehicle industry; Medical instruments and apparatus industry; Management; Measuring instruments; Natural gas pipelines; Notions (Merchandise); Newspaper publishing; Navigation equipment industry; National security; Office management; Office equipment and supplies; Petroleum refineries; Photographic industry; Paper folding (Graphic design); Public utilities; Paper products industry; Political participation; Plastics industry and trade; Pharmaceutical industry; Paint industry and trade; Public administration; Public opinion polls; Paper bag industry; Retail trade; Rug and carpet industry; Railroads; Rubber industry and trade; Railroad equipment industry; Roller bearings; Security systems industry; Service industries; Social security; Shipment of goods; Sanitary supply industry; Soybean industry; Slaughtering and slaughter-houses; Transportation equipment industry.; Telecommunication.; Trucking industry.; Trucks--Design and construction.; Textile industry.; Trade associations.; Tobacco industry.; Universities and colleges.; Vocational education.; Wood products.; Welding equipment industry.; Woolen goods industry.
Form and Genre Terms:
Records (documents); Publications (documents)
INFORMATION FOR USERS
Access Restrictions:
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
RELATED MATERIALS
Related Collections:
5880: Archives Organization File V, Additional Company Documents
5583/1: Archives Organization File (AOF) Part 1
5583/3: Archives Organization File (AOF) Part 3
5583/4: Archives Organization File (AOF) Part 4. Corporate and Organizational Publications
5583/5: Archives Organization File (AOF) Part 5
5583/6: Archives Organization File (AOF) Part 6
5956: Archives Organization File Additional records
CONTAINER LIST
- Box: 46, folder: 1 (Box 46, Folder 1)
  - Item 1: Individual Effort: The Key To Success, Publication (Box 46, Folder 1)
    May. Item is in English.
  - Item 2: Annual Report 1956, Publication (Box 46, Folder 1)
    Item is in English.
  - Item 3: MBW News, Publication (Box 46, Folder 1)
    May 17. Item is in English.
  - Item 4: News, Publication (Box 46, Folder 1)
    June 4. Item is in English.
  - Item 5: Self-Renewal, Publication (Box 46, Folder 1)
    September 30. Item is in English.
  - Item 6: News, Publication (Box 46, Folder 1)
  - Item 7: mbw news, Publication (Box 46, Folder 1)
    March 15. Item is in English.
  - Item 8: telephone Review Annual Report Issue, Publication (Box 46, Folder 1)
  - Item 9: New York Telephone Company Annual Report 1964, Publication (Box 46, Folder 1)
  - Item 10: Films, Publication (Box 46, Folder 1)
  - Item 11: Films, Publication (Box 46, Folder 1)
  - Item 12: Annual Report 1951, Publication (Box 46, Folder 1)
  - Item 13: Annual Report 1950, Publication (Box 46, Folder 1)
  - Item 14: 1953 Annual Report, Publication (Box 46, Folder 1)
  - Item 15: Annual Report 1951, Publication (Box 46, Folder 1)
  - Item 16: 1957 Annual Report New York Telephone Company, Publication (Box 46, Folder 1)
  - Item 17: Annual Report 1955, Publication (Box 46, Folder 1)
  - Item 18: 1956 Annual Report, Publication (Box 46, Folder 1)
  - Item 19: 1955 annual report, Publication (Box 46, Folder 1)
  - Item 20: Cues To Better Service, Publication (Box 46, Folder 1)
  - Item 21: Topics For Telephone People, Publication (Box 46, Folder 1)
    December. Item is in English.
  - Item 22: 1954 Annual Report, Publication (Box 46, Folder 1)
  - Item 23: 1954 Annual Report, Publication (Box 46, Folder 1)
  - Item 24: Annual Report 1952, Publication (Box 46, Folder 1)
  - Item 25: New York Telephone Company Annual Report, Publication (Box 46, Folder 1)
  - Item 26: 1959 Annual Report, Publication (Box 46, Folder 1)
  - Item 27: Trends Of Customer Opinion Fall 1964 Survey, Publication (Box 46, Folder 1)
    Fall. Item is in English.
  - Item 28: New York Telephone Company Annual Report 1973, Publication (Box 46, Folder 1)
  - Item 29: Youand communications, Publication (Box 46, Folder 1)
  - Item 30: The Challenge Of Change for graduates in enginering, mathematics, physics, Publication (Box 46, Folder 1)
  - Item 31: The Challenge Of Change for graduates in busines, liberal arts, social science, Publication (Box 46, Folder 1)
  - Item 32: when a girl makes up her mind, Publication (Box 46, Folder 1)
    February. Item is in English.
  - Item 33: Welcome To Your New Job, Publication (Box 46, Folder 1)
  - Item 34: For Your Information, Publication (Box 46, Folder 1)
  - Item 35: Your New Job- "Let's Talk It Over", Publication (Box 46, Folder 1)
  - Item 36: Colds Health Library Vol. II, Publication (Box 46, Folder 1)
  - Item 37: Now That You Belong, Publication (Box 46, Folder 1)
    November. Item is in English.
  - Item 38: Accounting Department Program 1955, Publication (Box 46, Folder 1)
    January 31. Item is in English.
  - Item 39: Some Facts About the Personnel Work of the New York Telephone Company, Publication (Box 46, Folder 1)
    January 1. Item is in English.
  - Item 40: your Job and your Company, Publication (Box 46, Folder 1)
  - Item 41: Challenge and Opportunity, Publication (Box 46, Folder 1)
  - Item 42: career development at New York Telephone Compan administration engineering sales- marketing, Publication (Box 46, Folder 1)
  - Item 43: Report On Traffic Employment Study Upstate Area Central Division, Publication (Box 46, Folder 1)
  - Item 44: Some facts about New York Telephone, Publication (Box 46, Folder 1)
  - Item 45: the service representative, Publication (Box 46, Folder 1)
  - Item 46: Something to look into!, Publication (Box 46, Folder 1)
  - Item 47: a good jobwith a winning team, Publication (Box 46, Folder 1)
  - Item 48: Futures In Management, Publication (Box 46, Folder 1)
  - Item 49: Join Our Action Team!, Publication (Box 46, Folder 1)
  - Item 50: Challenging Job in Communications With the Bell Telephone Companies, Publication (Box 46, Folder 1)
  - Item 51: Recruiting And Selelcting Employees, Publication (Box 46, Folder 1)
    January. Item is in English.
  - Item 52: the service representative, Publication (Box 46, Folder 1)
  - Item 53: Helpful Hints for getting your First Job, Publication (Box 46, Folder 1)
  - Item 54: the modern telephone operator, Publication (Box 46, Folder 1)
  - Item 55: join a People CompanyNew York Telephone, Publication (Box 46, Folder 1)
  - Item 56: New York Telephone, Publication (Box 46, Folder 1)
  - Item 57: Careers In Communications 194 Summer Program For College Men, Publication (Box 46, Folder 1)
  - Item 58: Hey-Look us over, Publication (Box 46, Folder 1)
  - Item 59: Absence Control, Publication (Box 46, Folder 1)
    March. Item is in English.
  - Item 60: Labor-Management Relations, Publication (Box 46, Folder 1)
  - Item 61: Catalog Of Management Training Courses, Publication (Box 46, Folder 1)
    September 1. Item is in English.
- Box: 46, folder: 2 (Box 46, Folder 2)
  - Item 1: 1965 Jounralism Graduates, Publication (Box 46, Folder 2)
  - Item 2: 1965 Annual Report from The Newspaper Fund, Publication (Box 46, Folder 2)
  - Item 3: Newspaper Personnel Relations Association, Publication (Box 46, Folder 2)
  - Item 4: Report To The Membership 1959-1962, Publication (Box 46, Folder 2)
  - Item 5: Newspaper Personnel Relations Association, Publication (Box 46, Folder 2)
  - Item 6: Newspaper Personnel Relations Association, Publication (Box 46, Folder 2)
  - Item 7: Newspaper Personnel Relations Association, Publication (Box 46, Folder 2)
  - Item 8: Supplementary Reports On 1962 NPRA Conference Labor Discussions, Publication (Box 46, Folder 2)
  - Item 9: Newspaper Persnnel Relations Conference, Los Angeles, June 28, 1962, Publication (Box 46, Folder 2)
    June 28. Item is in English.
  - Item 10: Newspaper Personnel Relations Association, Publication (Box 46, Folder 2)
  - Item 11: Newspaper Personnel Relations Association, Publication (Box 46, Folder 2)
- Box: 46, folder: 3 (Box 46, Folder 3)
  - Item 1: NPRA News, Publication (Box 46, Folder 3)
    July-August. Item is in English.
  - Item 2: Newspaper Personnel Relations Association, Publication (Box 46, Folder 3)
  - Item 3: NPRA 15th Annual Conference, Publication (Box 46, Folder 3)
    May 2-4. Item is in English.
- Box: 46, folder: 4 (Box 46, Folder 4)
  - Item 1: NPRA News, Publication (Box 46, Folder 4)
  - Item 2: NPRA News, Publication (Box 46, Folder 4)
    November-December. Item is in English.
  - Item 3: NPRA News, Publication (Box 46, Folder 4)
    September-October. Item is in English.
  - Item 4: NPRA News, Publication (Box 46, Folder 4)
  - Item 5: NPRA News, Publication (Box 46, Folder 4)
  - Item 6: NPRA News, Publication (Box 46, Folder 4)
  - Item 7: NPRA News, Publication (Box 46, Folder 4)
  - Item 8: NPRA News, Publication (Box 46, Folder 4)
    August. Item is in English.
  - Item 9: NPRA News, Publication (Box 46, Folder 4)
  - Item 10: NPRA News, Publication (Box 46, Folder 4)
    April. Item is in English.
  - Item 11: NPRA News, Publication (Box 46, Folder 4)
  - Item 12: NPRA News, Publication (Box 46, Folder 4)
    October. Item is in English.
  - Item 13: Newspaper Personnel Relations Association, Publication (Box 46, Folder 4)
  - Item 14: NPRA News, Publication (Box 46, Folder 4)
  - Item 15: Excerpts from an addrss by James B. Stickley, Publication (Box 46, Folder 4)
    May 3. Item is in English.
  - Item 16: NPRA News, Publication (Box 46, Folder 4)
  - Item 17: NPRA News, Publication (Box 46, Folder 4)
    March-April. Item is in English.
  - Item 18: NPRA News, Publication (Box 46, Folder 4)
    September. Item is in English.
  - Item 19: NPRA News, Publication (Box 46, Folder 4)
  - Item 20: NPRA News, Publication (Box 46, Folder 4)
  - Item 21: NPRA News, Publication (Box 46, Folder 4)
  - Item 22: NPRA News, Publication (Box 46, Folder 4)
  - Item 23: NPRA News, Publication (Box 46, Folder 4)
    June. Item is in English.
  - Item 24: NPRA News, Publication (Box 46, Folder 4)
  - Item 25: NPRA News, Publication (Box 46, Folder 4)
  - Item 26: NPRA News, Publication (Box 46, Folder 4)
  - Item 27: NPRA News, Publication (Box 46, Folder 4)
  - Item 28: NPRA News, Publication (Box 46, Folder 4)
  - Item 29: NPRA News, Publication (Box 46, Folder 4)
  - Item 30: NPRA News, Publication (Box 46, Folder 4)
  - Item 31: NPRA News, Publication (Box 46, Folder 4)
  - Item 32: NPRA News, Publication (Box 46, Folder 4)
  - Item 33: NPRA News, Publication (Box 46, Folder 4)
- Box: 46, folder: 5 (Box 46, Folder 5)
  - Item 1: The New York Times Major Medical Plan, Publication (Box 46, Folder 5)
  - Item 2: Retirement Annuity Plan of The New York Times Company, Publication (Box 46, Folder 5)
  - Item 3: Employe Handbook, Publication (Box 46, Folder 5)
  - Item 4: Confidential Removal Report, Publication (Box 46, Folder 5)
  - Item 5: The New York Times, Publication (Box 46, Folder 5)
  - Item 6: Application for Employment by The New York Times, Publication (Box 46, Folder 5)
  - Item 7: The New York Times Employe Biographical Summary, Publication (Box 46, Folder 5)
  - Item 8: New Employe Kit, Publication (Box 46, Folder 5)
- Box: 46, folder: 6 (Box 46, Folder 6)
  - Item 1: Times Talk, Publication (Box 46, Folder 6)
  - Item 2: The New York Times Annual Report 1966, Publication (Box 46, Folder 6)
  - Item 3: The New York Times Annual Report 1962, Publication (Box 46, Folder 6)
  - Item 4: Times Talk Season's Greetings, Publication (Box 46, Folder 6)
  - Item 5: The new York Times Annual Report 1959, Publication (Box 46, Folder 6)
  - Item 6: Times Talk, Publication (Box 46, Folder 6)
  - Item 7: Times Talk, Publication (Box 46, Folder 6)
  - Item 8: The New York Times Company Annual Report 1957, Publication (Box 46, Folder 6)
- Box: 46, folder: 7 (Box 46, Folder 7)
  - Item 1: Supplementary Index of Publications The newcomen Society in North America, Publication (Box 46, Folder 7)
    April 1. Item is in English.
  - Item 2: Index of Publications (1933-1961) The Newcomen Society In North America, Publication (Box 46, Folder 7)
- Box: 46, folder: 8 (Box 46, Folder 8)
  - Item 1: Eaton Yale & Towne: A Corporate Portrait, Publication (Box 46, Folder 8)
    By E. L. Ludvigsen. December. Item is in English.
  - Item 2: Supplement To The Index Of Publications Of The Newcomen Society In North America January 1962 Through November 1970 Newcomen Publications Numbers 679 Through 904, Publication (Box 46, Folder 8)
  - Item 3: Index of Publications (1933-1961) The Newcomen Society in North America, Publication (Box 46, Folder 8)
  - Item 4: Index of Publications (1933-1961) The Newcomen Society in North America, Publication (Box 46, Folder 8)
- Box: 46, folder: 9 (Box 46, Folder 9)
  - Item 1: Niagara's Pioneers, Publication (Box 46, Folder 9)
    By Merrill Denison. Item is in English.
- Box: 46, folder: 10 (Box 46, Folder 10)
  - Item 1: Port of Buffalo 1967 Handbook, Publication (Box 46, Folder 10)
  - Item 2: Port of Buffalo 1967 Handbook, Publication (Box 46, Folder 10)
- Box: 46, folder: 11 (Box 46, Folder 11)
  - Item 1: Niagara Mohawk News, Publication (Box 46, Folder 11)
  - Item 2: Annual Report 1950, Publication (Box 46, Folder 11)
  - Item 3: Niagara Mohawk News, Publication (Box 46, Folder 11)
    October-November. Item is in English.
  - Item 4: Niagara Mohawk News, Publication (Box 46, Folder 11)
- Box: 46, folder: 12 (Box 46, Folder 12)